Contact

+4915165444489 (Mobile) mail@marcusschiesser.de

www.linkedin.com/in/ marcusschiesser (LinkedIn) github.com/marcusschiesser (Portfolio) schiesser-it.com (Company)

Top Skills

Extract, Transform, Load (ETL)

Data Analysis

Data Warehousing

Languages

English (Full Professional)

Spanish (Limited Working)

Chinese (Limited Working)

French (Elementary)

German (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Deep Learning Specialization

Sequence Models

Structuring Machine Learning Projects

Python and Statistics for Financial Analysis

Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization

Publications

Workshop Java EE 7

Marcus Schiesser

Agentic RAG for Enterprises

Germany

Summary

Marcus Schiesser is a pragmatic software engineer building Al applications for enterprise-level businesses.

His diverse expertise spans data engineering, software architecture, and leadership, highlighted by his successful establishment of development offices in Asia for two startups.

Besides, he loves to share his industry knowledge part-time as a lecturer on backend development at Reutlingen University.

Experience

Schiesser IT
Al Engineer / Owner
June 2023 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Knowledge Foundation @ Reutlingen University University Lecturer
April 2021 - Present (3 years 4 months)

Teaching backend development in Go to graduate students

Zeppelin Group Splunk Specialist November 2021 - June 2023 (1 year 8 months) Munich, Bavaria, Germany

- Built multiple customer-facing data applications using an innovative cloudnative architecture including Splunk Enterprise on Kubernetes
- Improved Kubernetes support of Splunk's deep-learning solution DSDL

Glasnostic Inc.

CTO & Co-Founder

October 2016 - October 2021 (5 years 1 month)

- Set up and led a development office of 10+ engineers and designers in Taipei
- We created a dedicated runtime control layer for the cloud-native enterprise
- Supported the sales team selling the solution

Kosmos Systems AG Director Office Taiwan May 2013 - April 2018 (5 years)

Taipei City, Taiwan

- Set up and led a development office of 10+ engineers in Taipei
- We implemented and maintained the market-leading front-office solution for private banks in Germany and Switzerland

DB Systel GmbH
Technical Architect
September 2010 - September 2012 (2 years 1 month)
Frankfurt, Germany

Responsible for the architecture of two systems related to ticket machines: The first for processing the booking data, the second for the administration of maintenance orders

Prior Professional Experience Lead Software Engineer February 2002 - September 2010 (8 years 8 months) Germany

Development of various large-scale enterprise applications for DAX 30 companies.

Industries: automotive, banking, and telecommunication

Education

ESB Business School, Reutlingen University Master of Business Administration (MBA), International Marketing · (2004 - 2006)

University of Tübingen Diploma, Computer Science · (1997 - 2002)